Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Prisoners Rights TAM.512
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Prisoners Rights
2007-
TAM.512
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
33.0 websites and 435.8 GB.
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States. The collection contains periodically archived websites relating to U.S. prisoners' civil rights, the prison industrial complex, sentencing policy (including drug sentencing), discrimination against minorities, solitary confinement and other Eighth Amendment related issues, and also websites of U.S. entities' efforts on behalf of prisoners worldwide. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of this finding aid) to access the archive, then use the site list to select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
Contains websites relating to U.S. prisoners' civil rights, the prison industrial comples, sentencing policy (including drug sentencing), discrimination against minorities, solitary confinement and other Eighth Amendment related issues, and also websites of U.S. entities' efforts on behalf of prisoners worldwide. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of this finding aid) to access the archive, then use the site list to select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Prisoners Rights (U.S.), was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the website W eb Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
United States. Constitution. 8th Amendment.; African American prisoners.; Convict labor |z United States.; Drugs |x Law and legislation |z United States.; Prison-industrial complex |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States.; Prisons |z United States.; Sensory deprivation.; Sentences (Criminal procedure) |z United States.; Solitary confinement |z United States.
- Prisoners Rights Web Archive, 2007-
  - American Gulag, 3/15/2011
  - Attica is All of Us, 5/2/2012-
  - Breakthechains.info, 8/11/2010-
  - Business of Detention, 3/10/2012-9/9/2012
  - Campaign to End the Death Penalty, 4/27/2012-
  - Detention Watch Network, 3/05/2012-
  - FedCURE, 3/08/2012-
  - Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC, 12/23/2008-
  - Free Eddie Conway, 5/6/2012-
  - Free Fahad, 9/14/2010-
  - Jericho Movement, 03/26/2009-
  - Justice for Lynne Stewart, 07/06/2009-
  - Justice Policy Institute, 3/10/2012-
  - Legal Services for Prisoners With Children, 3/2/2012-
  - Mumia's Freedom Journal, 09/28/2007-1/22/2009
  - National Committee to Free the Cuban Five, 08/08/2009-
  - Nebraskans for Justice, 4/28/2012-
  - November Coalition, 05/07/2008-
  - Prison Activist Resource Center, 08/31/2009-
  - Prison Radio, 3/05/2012-
  - Prisoner Solidarity, 3/5/2012-
  - The Real Cost of Prison Project, 3/03/2012-
  - Safe Street Arts, 3/02/2012-
  - The Sentencing Project, 3/9/2012-
  - Stopmax: American Friends Service Committee (AFSC), 03/25/2009-
  - Sundiata Acoli Freedom Campaign (SAFC), 5/4/2012-
  - Thousand Kites, 3/08/2012-
  - William Moses Kunstler Fund for Racial Justice, 07/22/2009
  - Women and Prison, 3/04/2012-